<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[David Stump]]></title>
  <link href="http://davidstump.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://davidstump.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-31T16:47:27-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://davidstump.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Stump]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Add A Simple Git Timesheet]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidstump.github.com/blog/2012/12/31/add-a-simple-git-timesheet/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-31T15:06:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidstump.github.com/blog/2012/12/31/add-a-simple-git-timesheet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the end of each day, I find myself crawling through the git logs to record my activities for the day on our timesheet software. It eventually occurred to me that with a few super simple arguments passed to the <code>git log</code> command, I could have a basic output of my timesheet for that day.</p>

<p>Step 1. Edit Your bash_profile file:</p>

<pre><code> $ subl ~/.bash_profile
</code></pre>

<p>Step 2. Add an alias to your profile:</p>

<pre><code> git log --oneline --author="`git config --get user.name`" --since='6am'
</code></pre>

<p>Step 3. Save your profile</p>

<p>Step 4. Check your daily timesheet:</p>

<pre><code> david:~/Projects/octopress❮source❯$ timesheet
      2a08dac Adjust navigation mobile styles and hide search field
      816cfef Apply custom style to site
      b96240c Add Murky-Mussels Theme
</code></pre>

<p>Nothing complicated at all, but hopefully someone else finds this as helpful as I did. Thanks to <a href="http://twitter.com/chris_mccord">@chris_mccord</a> for adding the user.name snippet to this alias.</p>

<p>Cheers!<br/>
David</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Initial Commit.]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidstump.github.com/blog/2012/12/26/initial-commit/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-26T13:42:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidstump.github.com/blog/2012/12/26/initial-commit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Happy Blizzard 2012!</strong></p>

<p>It&#8217;s not quite New Year&#8217;s Eve, however, I thought I would get a jump start on a resolution early this year. The resolution idea comes from my awesome co-workers at <a href="http://littlelines.com">Littlelines</a> who each mentioned re-starting their blog presence and making an effort to write and share more in 2013. I love the developer community [specifically the Ruby/Rails community as of late] and the ease/effort with which help, advice, problems and solutions are shared and discussed. For this new year, I am planning to make a concerted effort to write, share and help the community that has helped in uncountable ways getting me where I am today [which is a pretty fantastic happy place!].</p>

<p>Perhaps this sentimental resolution is partially a result of a bit too much holiday cheer [by way of food, presents, family and one midwest blizzard], but a little more cheer throughout the non-holiday months couldn&#8217;t hurt anyone, right?</p>

<p>With that, I hope everyone had a relaxing holiday break and is pumped to start a brand new 2013 in a few days. Also, keep and eye out for some exciting Dayton Ruby Community news in the near future!!</p>

<p><strong>Cheers!</strong><br/>
<em>David</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
